（戦闘音）
（藍原延珠(あいはらえんじゅ)）
蓮太郎(れんたろう) 自衛隊 勝つかな？
Rentaro... Do you think the JASDF will win?
I'm not sure.
（里見(さとみ)蓮太郎）分からん
（戦闘音）
The fighting stopped.
（片桐(かたぎり)玉樹(たまき)）戦闘がやんだぞ
勝ったのか？
Did we win?
（蓮太郎･延珠）あっ
（一同）あ…
（人々の悲鳴）
そ… そ…
Th-Th-That's... impossible...
そんな バカな！
♪～
～♪
#11 The Heart of Taurus, The Spear of Light
（我堂(がどう)英彦(ひでひこ)）
総員 戦闘用意！
All hands prepare for battle!
（ティナ）お兄さん
Onii-san!
あれ
Look!
別動隊か
A detachment...
誰も気づいてねえぞ
No one else saw it...
挟み撃ちにされたら
俺たち全滅だ！
If they flank us, we're doomed!
（薙沢彰磨(なぎさわしょうま)）
だが 勝手に陣を離れるのは
However, leaving the camp would be a clear violation of our orders.
明確な命令違反だ
どうする？ 里見
What do you want to do, Satomi?
（片桐弓月(ゆづき)）あんたが決めて
You decide!
あたしたちは
リーダーの言うことを聞くから
We'll listen to our leader.
行こう！
Let's go!
（英彦）里見リーダー？
Leader Satomi?
どこへ行く！
列に戻れ！
Where are you going?
Return to your position!
くっ
はーっ！
（ガストレアの雄たけび）
（銃声）
（蓮太郎）マズい！
This isn't good!
（天童(てんどう)木更(きさら)）任せて
Leave it to me.
天童式抜刀術 一の型八番
Tendo Martial Arts Sword Drawing
First Style, Number 8:
無影無踪(むえいむそう)
Muei Muso!
ヒュ～
木更さん
Kisara-san...
あ…
（布施(ふせ) 翠(みどり)）里見リーダー
Leader Satomi,
終わりました
we've finished.
（蓮太郎）強い
We're strong...
これなら…
At this rate...
よし 急いで戻るぞ！
All right! Let's hurry back.
（一同）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
あっ
（ガストレアの雄たけび）
クソッ
Damn it...
At this rate, we're all done for.
このままじゃ 全滅だ
あっ
あいつは…
That's...
みんなは ここで援護を頼む！
（木更）うん
All of you, stay here and back me up!
（蓮太郎）おい！
Hey!
あんた 今すぐ 撤退の指示を出せ！
Hurry and tell everyone to fall back!
（英彦）やあ
Well,
里見リーダーじゃないか
if it isn't Leader Satomi.
君は 光の槍(やり)を見たかい？
Have you seen the Spear of Light?
光の槍？
Spear of Light?
あんなものがあるんなら
With that thing on their side,
僕らには 最初から
勝ち目はなかったんだよ
we never stood a chance from the start.
ああ
Oh...
心音(ここね)だよ
This is Kokone.
最後まで 一緒にいようって
ずっと 手を握り合っていたんだ
We were holding hands the whole time,
saying we'd be together until the end.
そこを光の槍に襲われた
And then the Spear of Light attacked.
フッフッ
ハハハハ…
フハハハハハ…
ああー！
うわー！
（蓮太郎）光の槍…
The Spear of Light...
（民警たち）うわー！
（アルデバランの雄たけび）
アルデバラン…
Alde... baran...
（民警）おい 見ろ！
Hey, look!
ガストレアが引いていくぞ！
The Gastrea are falling back!
（玉樹）ひでえもんだ
Man, this is awful.
一体 何人 死んだんだ？
Just how many people died?
（蓮太郎）たぶん 半数は
Probably about half...
敵だって だいぶ減っただろ
The enemy forces have
also dwindled, haven't they?
だが 減った分だけ増えている
（玉樹）えっ？
But whatever they lost, they gained back.
What?
民警 自衛隊含め
Including both civil officers and JASDF,
1000人以上は
ガストレア化しただろう
over a thousand have turned into Gastrea.
（玉樹）ってことは
ガストレア2000体に対して―
Meaning... there's only 500
of us against 2,000 of them?!
俺たちは500人!?
（蓮太郎）絶望的な数字だ
It's a despairing number...
あっ
（延珠）蓮太郎！
Rentaro!
蓮太郎！ イヒヒッ
あっ どうしたんだ？ それ
Where'd you get that?
かわいいだろう
手伝ってたら くれたのだ
Isn't it cute?
They gave it to me because I was helping!
ふーん
Huh...
邪魔になってたんじゃないのか？
You sure you weren't in the way?
とんでもない
Not at all.
ケガ人の手を握ってあげて
すごくいいって評判になってるわ
She holds the hands of the wounded...
They all say she's wonderful.
へえー
Huh...
妾(わらわ) 役に立ってる！
I am being useful!
はいはい
すげえよ お前は
Yeah, you're amazing, all right.
うおっ
（室戸(むろと) 菫(すみれ)）こんばんは 蓮太郎くん
Good evening, Rentaro-kun.
It's a beautiful night, isn't it?
いい夜だね
先生　どうして こんな所に？
Sensei, what are you doing here?
ここを統括するように
要請があってね
I was asked to supervise things here.
あんた 確か シェルターの抽選に
当たってたよな？
You won a spot in the shelter, didn't you?
当たったんじゃなくて
もらったんだよ
I didn't win it; they gave it to me.
日本最高の頭脳に死なれたら
困るってね
They said they couldn't allow the
greatest brain in Japan to die...
その場で 破り捨てたがね
Though, I ripped it up on the spot.
捨てるぐらいなら 誰かにやれよ
You could've given it to someone if you
were just going to throw it away.
（菫）誰に？
To who?
砂漠にコップ１杯の水が
あっても―
If there were only a cup
of water in the desert,
それを巡って
殺し合いが始まるだけだ
they'd just kill each other to get it.
今の東京エリアで―
I can't imagine we'd find
全員の喉を潤せるようなオアシスが
見つかるとは思えない
an oasis in the Tokyo Area that
could quench everyone's thirst.
私がここに来たのは
The reason I'm here is
この砂漠を抜けようと
もくろんだバカどもを
because I wanted to cheer on
the idiots who are trying to
応援してやりたくなったからだ
get out of the desert.
先生は もっと論理的な人間だと
思ってた
I thought you were a much
more logical person, Sensei.
人間は 論理でものを考え
感情で動くんだよ
Humans tend to think logically,
but their actions are driven by emotions.
行動したまえ 蓮太郎くん
Take action, Rentaro-kun.
立ち止まれば 死に追いつかれるよ
If you stop, death will catch up to you.
そうだな
Yeah, you're right...
ありがと 先生
Thanks, Sensei.
それと 延珠のことだけど
Also, about Enju...
クラスメートが亡くなった話なら
聞いている
If it's about her losing her
classmates, I've heard.
災難だったね
That was quite the tragedy.
先生 医者から見て
延珠はどうなんだ？
Sensei, from a doctor's
perspective, how's Enju doing?
安心したまえ
たぶん もう大丈夫だろう
Don't worry. I think she's all right.
延珠ちゃんのメンタルは―
Enju-chan's mental stability
is far stronger than we imagine.
私たちが思っているより
ずっと強い
ホントか!?
Really?
うたぐり深い男だねえ 君も
You're a very skeptical man, aren't you?
まっ 念のために事件のことを
思い出させるような言動は
Well, I'd avoid bringing up
anything that would remind her
of the incident, just in case.
慎みたまえ
さあ 君たちは
もう 帰って休みたまえ
You two should go back and rest now.
（木更･延珠）あっ
（一同）あっ
（木更）やだ なんか不気味
Ugh, this place is sort of creepy...
（延珠）
ここがそうなのか？ 蓮太郎
Is this the place, Rentaro?
（蓮太郎）彰磨兄(にい)の話だと
そのはずなんだが…
According to what Shoma-nii
said, it should be...
（ティナ）
あっ お兄さん いらっしゃい
Oh, welcome, Onii-san.
このホテル 住めるように
キレイにしておきましたよ
I've cleaned up this hotel,
so it'd be suitable for living.
いや 住むっつっても
数日間 借りるだけだから
Er, but we're only going to be
staying here for a few days...
それでも どうせなら
キレイなほうが
Still, would it not make you
happier if the place were clean?
うれしいじゃないですか
Who knew
（彰磨）まさか 真夏に
暖炉をたくはめになるとはな
we'd be lighting the fireplace
in the middle of summer?
舞い上がったモノリスの灰が
太陽を隠してるせいで
Because of the ashes from the Monolith
rising up and hiding the sun,
あと３日は寒いらしい
they say it'll be cold for the next three days.
（玉樹）飯の用意ができたぞ！
Food's ready.
（蓮太郎）うまいな
It's good.
（玉樹）ヘッ
どうよ 見直しただろ
See? Impressed, aren't you?
（弓月）
兄貴は 我が家のシェフなの
Bro's the chef in our house.
変態のあんたじゃ
足元にも及ばないんだからね
A pervert like you could never compare.
I guess you really can't
judge a book by its cover.
人は見かけによらないとは
このことだな
（延珠）蓮太郎
Rentaro.
アルデバランは
どうして逃げていったのだ？
Why did Aldebaran run away?
（蓮太郎）
ウワサ話なら飛び交ってるけど―
There are a lot of rumors going around,
but nobody knows for sure.
実際のところは分からねえ
（弓月）また ガストレアは
攻めてくるかな？
I wonder if the Gastrea will attack again...
（玉樹）代替えモノリスの完成まで
まだ３日あるからな
Not to mention, there are
three more days until the
substitute Monolith is complete.
里見くん ちょっといい？
Satomi-kun, do you have a sec?
（一同）ん？
（木更）光の槍に
手足を切断された患者さんを―
I observed some patients
who had their arms or legs
cut off by the Spear of Light...
診たんだけど―
彼らは例外なく
難聴や視野狭窄(きょうさく)といった
All of them are experiencing
deafness or loss of sight,
水銀中毒の兆候が見られるの
which are symptoms of mercury poisoning.
水銀…
Mercury?
お兄さん
Onii-san, there's something I'd like to report
私も その件で
１つ報告したいことがあります
about that matter, as well.
戦闘中 シェンフィールドで
５キロ先に
During the battle, using Shenfield,
I located a Gastrea,
水銀を射出したと思われる
ガストレアを捕捉しました
five kilometers away, that I
believe was shooting out mercury.
どんなヤツだった
What did it look like?
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry...
シェンフィールドに
画像を送信する機能はないんです
Shenfield doesn't have the
ability to send images.
ただ 大きさは かなりありました
However, it was rather large.
おそらく ステージⅣです
I would say it was a Stage Four.
（男性）失礼します
Excuse me.
（一同）あ…
（男性）里見リーダー
Leader Satomi.
我堂団長から
お呼びがかかりました
Commander Gado sent out a summons for you.
至急 仮設本部までお越しください
Please report to the temporary
headquarters at once.
我堂が…
Gado?
Have a seat.
（我堂長政(ながまさ)）かけたまえ
That's...
あ… あんた それ…
Indeed.
ああ
I got it when I fought with it.
ヤツと一戦 交えたときにな
You mean Aldebaran?
（蓮太郎）ヤツって
アルデバランのことか？
That's right.
そうだ
However, it didn't take my leg;
だが この足は奪われたのではない
I let 'im have it.
くれてやったのだよ
How was my son, Hidehiko,
in his final moments?
せがれの英彦は
どのような最期を遂げた？
He fought very bravely.
立派に戦ってたよ
I'm the one who had him
become a civil officer.
あれに民警をやらせたのは私だ
If I had known this was going to happen, I'd have let him do what he wanted.
こんなことになるなら
好きな道を歩かせてやるべきだった
Gado, don't you think that the
enemy has too much of a lead on us?
（蓮太郎）我堂 今回の敵は―
統率がとれすぎていると
思わないか？
What are you trying to say?
何が言いたい？
After the JASDF won the earlier battle,
先の戦いで快勝した自衛隊が―
why did they lose so quickly this time?
なぜ 今回は
あんなにあっさりやられたのか
And when Aldebaran was hurt,
アルデバランが傷ついたとき―
why did the surrounding Gastrea form a wall?
なぜ 周囲のガストレアが
壁になったのか？
The answer is... pheromones.
その答えは フェロモンだ
Are you saying it's releasing pheromones?
フェロモンを
噴出しているというのか？
The thing that gathered the
Gastrea around Aldebaran was
（蓮太郎）アルデバランの周りに
ガストレアを集めたのは―
the aggregation pheromone.
“集合フェロモン”だ
It seems Aldebaran is using
pheromones for various purposes
おそらく アルデバランは
フェロモンを使い分けて―
to keep total control over the pack.
完璧に群れを統率してるんだ
That being the case,
だとすれば アルデバランを倒せば
群れは崩壊する
if we defeat Aldebaran,
the pack will be destroyed.
We can win!
俺たちは勝てる
（長政）うむ
That was a very helpful insight.
大変 参考になる意見だったよ
But I will let you in on some information
that you're not aware of...
では 私も君が知らない情報を
１つ提供しよう
There is no way to defeat Aldebaran.
アルデバランを倒す方法はない
Aldebaran is immortal.
ヤツは不死身だ
えっ？
My Varanium blade split its head open
私のバラニウムの剣は
ヤツの頭部を断ち割り
and pierced through upon reversal.
返す刃(やいば)で貫いた
I am sure I dealt damage
to its brain and heart...
確かに 脳と心臓に
ダメージを与えた
However, it didn't fall...
しかし ヤツは倒れず
In the next instant, although slowly,
it began to regenerate itself.
次の瞬間 ゆっくりとだが
傷の再生を始めた
No...
そんな…
And that's not the only trump card they have.
（長政）しかも
切り札は それだけではない
The Gastrea with the Spear of Light...
光の槍を持つガストレア
It's been identified to be as
great a threat as Aldebaran.
ヤツは アルデバランと並ぶ脅威と
認定された
Codename: Pleiades.
コードネームは“プレヤデス”だ
Pleiades...
プレヤデス
We cannot win simply by defeating Aldebaran.
（長政）
アルデバランを倒すだけでは―
我々は勝利できない
Even if we try to defeat the king,
the queen will stand in the way.
キングを倒そうとしても
必ず クイーンが立ちはだかる
In order to win this game,
eliminating the queen is essential.
このゲームにおいて
クイーンの排除は勝利の絶対条件だ
Because of that, we must make
a very difficult decision today.
そのうえで 我々は今日
つらい決断を下さなければならない
Leader Satomi.
里見リーダー
In the midst of maneuvers,
you and your adjuvant
君と君のアジュバントは
作戦行動中に英彦の陣を離れ
strayed from Hidehiko's camp
and acted on your own.
単独行動をした
Wait a minute.
待ってくれ！
That was to eliminate
the enemy's detachment—
俺たちは 敵の別動隊を
たたくために…
That doesn't change the fact
that you disobeyed orders!
（長政）命令違反は命令違反だ！
Your actions were equal to fleeing
in the presence of the enemy,
君たちの行いは
敵前逃亡に等しく
causing a potentially lethal
disturbance in the civil officer ranks.
他の民警に 致命的な動揺を与えた
You must pay for that.
そのツケは 払わなければならない
Leader Satomi, I hereby disband your adjuvant
里見リーダー
君のアジュバントを解体し
and sentence you to capital punishment.
君を極刑に処する！
You can't be serious!
（蓮太郎）ふざけるな！
うっ
ぐっ
（剣を抜く音）
Leader Satomi, are you
prepared to die once again?
里見リーダー
君は もう一度
死んでみる覚悟はあるか
I believe that if we can defeat Pleiades,
私は プレヤデスを倒せば―
we can find a hole in the wall
we are currently up against.
この閉塞(へいそく)した状況を
打開する糸口になると思っている
And so...
そこでだ
I want you to infiltrate enemy
territory and destroy Pleiades.
君には 敵地に単独で潜入し
プレヤデスを撃滅してほしい
You've shown your true colors...
（蓮太郎）本性を現しやがったな
You cannot decline.
君に拒否権はないのだよ
In return, I promise your
adjuvant will not be punished.
その代わり
君のアジュバントの罪は―
問わないことを約束する
You conniving old man...
タヌキじじいが…
（寝息）
I'm sorry, Enju.
すまん 延珠
Where are you going, Satomi-kun?
（木更）どこに行くの？ 里見くん
To the bathroom.
Are you going to follow me there?
トイレだよ
ついてくんのか
With all that luggage?
そんな荷物 持って？
I can bring whatever I want!
何を持ってこうが 俺の勝手だろ！
So the punishment wasn't just the
disbanding of the adjuvant, was it?
処分は アジュバントの
解散だけじゃなかったのね
But by yourself...
けど １人でなんて
死にに行くようなものよ！
That's the same as going off to die!
Someone has to take responsibility.
誰かが責任を
取らなきゃなんないんだ
Let's run away.
逃げましょう
To where?
どこに？
W-Well...
そ… それは…
There's nowhere left to run in the Tokyo Area.
（蓮太郎）もう 東京エリアに
逃げ場所なんてない
If we don't stop it here, we'll die,
no matter where we run.
ここで食い止めなきゃ
どこに逃げても死ぬ
That's the one thing we have to avoid.
それだけは 避けなきゃ
Thanks, Kisara-san.
ありがとう 木更さん
You really are
ホントに おバカなんだから…
an idiot.
（オオカミの遠ぼえ）
くっ
うっ
ぐっ… うっ うわっ！
うわー！
（蓮太郎）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（オオカミのうなり声）
（ケルベロスの雄たけび）
I guess this is it...
ここまでか
うっ… くっ
あ…
（蛭子(ひるこ)影胤(かげたね)）フフフフフ…
（蓮太郎）はっ
Well, fancy meeting you here...
（影胤）
こんな所で出会うとは 奇遇だね
Satomi-kun.
里見くん
So you were alive...
生きていたのか 蛭子影胤！
Hiruko Kagetane!
（影胤）フフフ…
Would you kindly put your gun down already?
そろそろ
銃を下ろしてくれんかね？
No.
断る
Have you already forgotten who it was
that gave you bandages and antibiotics?
（影胤）包帯や抗生物質を
提供しているのは誰なのか―
もう忘れたのかね？
And you guys haven't forgotten
what you've done, have you?
（蓮太郎）てめえらこそ―
自分がしたことを
忘れたんじゃねえだろうな
What are you doing here?
どうして ここにいる？
Are you involved in that
geezer's schemes again?
また じじいの悪だくみに
加担してんのか？
I have no comment.
（影胤）ノーコメントだよ
Where's Enju?
（蛭子小比奈(こひな)）延珠は？
Did she die?
死んだの？
She's alive. We're moving separately for now.
生きてるよ
別行動中だ
Oh, good! Enju...
そう　延珠
I want to see her...
会いたいな 斬りたいな
会いたいな 斬りたいな…
I want to cut her...
I want to see her... I want to cut her...
Satomi-kun, one could ask
what it is you're doing here.
（影胤）里見くん
君こそ なぜ こんな所に？
I'm here to defeat Pleiades.
プレヤデスを倒すためだ
Pleiades?
（影胤）プレヤデス？
It's a Gastrea that shoots out mercury.
水銀を打ち出すガストレアだ
Oh, right. I did see something like that.
（影胤）ああ いたね そんなのが
I was watching the battle yesterday.
昨日の戦いなら
見物させてもらったよ
You were watching?
見物だと？
Why didn't you participate?
どうして 戦いに参加しない？
What, exactly, waits
for me after this battle?
（影胤）
戦って その先に何がある？
Peace.
平和だ
I've never wished for such a thing.
（影胤）フッ
一度として 望んだことはない
You truly are broken.
お前は壊れている
Have you ever even considered me normal?
（影胤）今日の今日まで
私がまともだとでも？
Why do you wear a mask?
お前 どうして仮面をかぶってる？
（影胤）フッ
Would you like to see my face?
私の素顔を見たいかい？
No.
（蓮太郎）いや
That is the correct answer.
（影胤）正解だ
見たら きっと後悔する
You would assuredly regret seeing it.
Are you scarred or something?
（蓮太郎）傷でもあんのかよ
（影胤）フフッ…
The thing under this mask...
この仮面の下にあるのはね―
is your own face.
君の顔だよ
Don't mess with me.
ふざけんじゃねえ！
We possess powers that are beyond humans.
（影胤）我々は 人をして
人を超えた力を持っている
When faced with senseless violence,
you must have thought,
君も理不尽な暴力にさらされたとき
思ったはずだ
"I have enough power inside me
to turn you all into ground meat!"
俺の中には お前らを
簡単にひき肉にできるほどの―
力があるんだぞ と…
I've been carrying that out.
私は それを実行してきた
That's why you hate me.
だから 君は 私を憎悪するんだ
You envy me.
君は 私が羨ましい
Shut up!
黙れ！
However, Satomi-kun...
（影胤）だがね 里見くん
Just as you feel about me, I, too, envy you.
君と同じように
私も君を羨望しているのだよ
Living so comfortably in
your world of light...
光の世界で
ぬくぬくと生きている君が―
I can't help but despise you!
呪わしてくてたまらない！
Come with me, my friend.
私と共に来い 友よ
I shall teach you pleasure.
君に快楽を教えてやる
I will never mistake how I use my powers!
俺は 力の使い方を
間違えたりしない
（影胤）フフフフ…
I shall make a prediction, Satomi-kun.
予言しよう 里見くん
You will definitely come to this side...
君は 必ず こちらに来る
Without fail.
きっとだ
（鳥のさえずり）
Did they already leave?
もう 行ったのか？
A river...
川か…
Oh, there you are.
（影胤）こんな所にいたのかね
There's something I forgot to tell you.
君に伝え忘れたことがあった
We happened to bump into this
Gastrea named Pleiades yesterday.
私たちは 昨日―
プレヤデスとかいうガストレアに
遭遇した
Where?!
どこで!?
Follow the river upstream.
（影胤）そこの川に沿って
上流に向かえばいい
Why are you telling me this?
どうして 俺にそのことを教える？
Well, if I must give a reason,
（影胤）さて 強いて言うなら
君が気に入っているからかね
it might be because I happen to like you.
（蓮太郎）フンッ
What are you doing?
なんのつもりだ？
You just happen to be
going the same way we are.
（影胤）私たちの進行方向に
君がいるだけだが？
Do whatever you want.
（蓮太郎）勝手にしろ！
And that's precisely what we shall do.
（影胤）そうさせてもらおう
♪～
～♪
#12 Crisis Point
This is the world that you wished for.
（影胤）これは 君の望んだ世界だ
君が始末をつけろ
You must make amends with it.
Please, Satomi-kun. Lead us.
（木更）里見くん お願い
私たちを導いて！
The final battle will be at
the Flames of Revolution.
（蓮太郎）
最終決戦の場所は“回帰の炎”だ